{
    "id": "253b45810a5843899aa30af985f0b162",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise (Gap Filling)",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "1efdf904158149e8b5a180b0febf3ad1",
            "title": "General Grammar Exercise (Gap Filling)",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "…………………………. you start now, you will be late for the party.",
                    "description": "Unless is similar to if not.",
                    "answers": [
                        "If",
                        "Without",
                        "Unless"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "He ………………………….. to be an actor.",
                    "description": "The present perfect is more common with always, ever, never etc.",
                    "answers": [
                        "always wanted",
                        "is always wanting",
                        "has always wanted"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "She has been absent ………………………. Monday.",
                    "description": "Since indicates the starting point.",
                    "answers": [
                        "for",
                        "from",
                        "since"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "They accused me ………………………… their conversation.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "to overhear",
                        "of overhearing",
                        "of overhear"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "She asked me if I ……………………….. a drink.",
                    "description": "When the main verb is in the past tense, use a past tense in the subordinate clause as well. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "want",
                        "wanted",
                        "had wanted"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ………………………….. TV at 8 o’clock yesterday evening.",
                    "description": "Use the past continuous to say that an activity was in progress at a particular point of time in the past. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "was watching",
                        "watched",
                        "had watched"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Ever since she returned to her native place she …………………………. Jobless.",
                    "description": "The present perfect is used to indicate time up to now.",
                    "answers": [
                        "was",
                        "is",
                        "has been"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I do not ………………………… his activities.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "approve to",
                        "approve with",
                        "approve of"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I will give him the message as soon as he ……………………………..",
                    "description": "When the main verb is in the future tense, use a present tense in the subordinate clause to refer to future time.",
                    "answers": [
                        "arrive",
                        "arrives",
                        "will arrive",
                        "arrived"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you ………………………… a little louder, I could hear you properly.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "speak",
                        "spoke",
                        "had spoken"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "My car is faster than …………………………….",
                    "description": "Yours means the same as your car.",
                    "answers": [
                        "you",
                        "your",
                        "yours"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "You need not ............................... the plants.",
                    "description": "When need is an auxiliary verb, it is followed by an infinitive without to.",
                    "answers": [
                        "water",
                        "to water"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}